Hey, and welcome back to Living in
Central Texas. [music] Last week I gave
you a dash cam tour of some of my
favorite communities near Lake Belton.
This should have given a really great
idea of the communities, the roads, the
vibe, and just the overall feel within
each of those communities.
>> [music]
>> Today, I wanted to take it one step
further and show you what some of the
homes in those communities [music]
actually look like, the price points,
and a map view of where each of those
are in proximity to each other [music]
and in relation to Central Texas. So, if
you're relocating to the Central Texas
area, moving to Belton, Texas, or you
just want to compare lake living, this
video should really help you narrow down
your search.
>> [music]
>> Okay, friends, welcome [music]
back. Today's video is going to be a
little bit different as I have Peanut
here with me today. She's officially
[music] 2 months old, but she's been my
little sidekick and hanging out with me
for the past couple months.
But, I wanted to do a follow-up video to
my last video where I took you on a dash
cam tour of some of the communities near
Lake [music] Belton. They're just some
of my favorite and more popular
communities. The weather wasn't so
great, but [music] it generally is nice
and sunny and beautiful. But, today's
video is going to help you see in
proximity [music]
where these communities are on the map,
and also [music] we're going to pop into
the MLS, which is the multiple listing
service where we as agents list the
houses for sale. It's going to give you
a great idea of price points, [music]
and then we'll take a look at some of
the pictures of the homes in those
communities. [music] All right, so when
we take a look at the map here, we have
Waco, Texas, Austin, Texas, is right
down here, just out of frame, and then
[music]
Lake Belton is right there. This is
Stillhouse Hollow Lake. It's another
lake in Belton. [music] Really great
communities around there, too, which I
can do at another time if you're
interested. But then we have I-35 that
runs through here. [music]
Kind of smack through the Temple-Belton
area. Again, Waco and then Austin. And
then you have Georgetown, [music]
Round Rock. And we'll zoom in a bit to
my neck of the woods. Again,
>> [music]
>> Lake Belton. I focused on these areas
right here. Belton, Temple. There's lots
of overlap. Again, you can be
>> [music]
>> in Temple but part of Belton school
district. There Everything's really
close to
>> [music]
>> everything. And then here's I-35.
Salado, Texas [music] is beautiful.
Again, uh kind of golf cart golf course
living. Really beautiful. More expensive
[music] price per square foot than the
Temple-Belton area. Little River
Academy, that's where my in-laws are
from. Uh quaint little town. [music] I
always say people that live there, they
don't ever want to leave. Same thing
with Troy, Texas.
And then through the through I-14,
[music]
we have Fort Hood.
We have Copperas Cove on the outskirts,
Killeen, Harker Heights, [music] and
Nolanville. All really great options if
you are looking to be in this area. But
[music] for this video, we focused on
Lake Belton and then a lot of
>> [music]
>> Morgan's Point Resort.
We'll zoom in a little bit further. We
have I-35 again, [music] which runs
through Temple-Belton. And then West
Adams, if you
Oops. That's not a very good artistic
ability.
West Adams.
>> [music]
>> If you saw my video on Temple, Texas, I
did a drive through the area and up West
Adams. [music] West Adams kind of the
main road that runs through east and
west Temple to Belton. [music]
And then 317
is the main
road that runs through [music]
north and south from Belton up to Temple
and through.
But,
you take West Adams,
>> [music]
>> you'll hit Morgan's Point Road, and
you can see
we turned right [music] on West Adams in
my video and turned into Morgan's Point.
So, right here
is Lago Terra. That was the first
community we checked out. Then we have
Rancho del Lago,
community number two.
And then [music] Cliffs at Lake Belton
was out here. But, today we're also
[music] going to look at a couple resale
homes for sale and
just some really optional options
[music] that I highlighted
just around
different parts of Lake Belton. All
right, [music] let's take a look. So,
first we're going to take a look at Lago
Terra. And [music] this again is the
MLS. This is where we as agents post
houses for sale. Lago Terra, so
currently there are
>> [music]
>> four houses for sale in Lago Terra. One
is actually under contract. [music]
And the price points range in this
community right now from [music] 679
up to 1.1 million. Average days on
market currently 28 42 [music] 133 235.
Square footage, the let's take a look at
this one.
First. Okay, [music] we're going to
start with the lower price point runs
one right now. This is 116 Vista de
Luna.
Four bed, three bath home.
2,777 [music]
square feet
on just under a quarter acre, built in
2023. Let's take a look at this pretty
[music] guy.
All of these I think were built by
Carothers that we're looking at right
now. [music] This one's
super
modern.
Uh we have
gas, so propane cuz there's no
>> [music]
>> natural gas out there, but propane
stove.
Accent and [music] ceilings, recessed
lighting, crown molding, beautiful
kitchen.
Great lighting.
Tile crown molding throughout. This is
the primary bedroom.
Primary bath, large walk-in closets.
Accent [music] and centered tub.
Dual vanities, beautiful walk-in shower.
Oh, [music] it's got the walk-through
car wash style shower.
Large closets.
>> [music]
>> Secondary beds and baths.
I'm going to kind of go through [music]
these semi fast so that we can look at a
few of them.
Utility sink [music] in the laundry
space.
Large
backyard with the
>> [music]
>> outdoor kitchen.
Look how large that yard is.
Garage [music] space.
Attic space.
And there you go.
Beautiful home.
Again, that one's [music] priced at 679,
originally 710. We're seeing that we're
seeing a lot of price drops on [music]
homes. And that was the 679. And then if
we go to
we'll go look at one of the more
expensive [music] ones. So this is Lago
Veneto Lane, 1,125,000.
It's been on the market 42 days.
>> [music]
>> Open floor plan home, four bed, four
full bath, 3,774
sq ft right here.
On a half acre, built [music] in 2022.
This looks like another Carothers. And
uh I what I like about this one is that
it has looks like great trees.
And out here in Morganton Point, the
builders trying to do a really good job
of retaining [music] those trees when
building their homes. So, you get a new
home on an established lot.
Has a beautiful pool. Oh my gosh, y'all,
look how beautiful that is. [music]
This decking around it,
spa,
sitting area over here.
You got your wood beams, [music]
stone fireplace. Looks like luxury vinyl
plank flooring, large gourmet kitchen
[music] with the gas fireplace. Sorry.
Um gas stove. [music]
Tons of cabinet space.
Open into the primary. Ooh, nice little
buffet bar area.
>> [music]
>> Love what they did with that space.
You have your wine fridge, [music] beer
fridge,
beverage fridge down there.
Primary. Oh my gosh, primary bedroom
[music] with that stone accent wall.
Super rare. I haven't seen that in
[music] very, very long time.
Tray ceilings.
Primary bath.
Some of the secondary
rooms.
Y'all, I feel like I'm [music] talking
like a robot. Last night was was not a
good night of baby sleep. She's been
sleeping like a a
but last night was not a good one. Okay,
so this is the laundry space with
[music] a utility sink,
mud bench.
Ooh, look at that fun flooring.
>> [music]
>> Fun tile in there.
And again, that gorgeous backyard, long,
beautiful drive with all those trees.
This is a
stunning home. [music]
And then,
we looked at this one in Toca. This is
the one that's under contract. [music]
But you can see the lake back here in
[music] proximity to the neighborhood.
This is the one that's currently under
contract.
But it was [music] priced at 797. They
dropped it to 796.
On the market [music] for 235 days, so I
don't know what it's under what it's
doing under contract, but
I mean, [music]
what it's under contract for.
And then the other, the final one
is [music] this one, and it's priced at
925.
.44 acre lot.
Four bed, [music] three full, two half
bath, 3,600 square feet, built in 2014,
so it's one of the older ones.
Circle drive.
Another pool.
Got a
>> [music]
>> room upstairs.
Beautiful tile.
Formal [music] dining space plus an
office.
Dark cabinets. [music] Kind of seeing
those trends back, the knotty alder
custom cabinets.
Laundry space. [music]
Primary. [music]
Primary bath.
Dual vanities, [music]
nice walk-in shower, huge closets.
Carothers does a great job of their
closet space. They [music]
go all the way up so that you can put
seasonal
clothing up there. This is the upstairs
[music] space on this one.
Awesome. Half bath. [music]
Got your pool, outdoor kitchen with a
fireplace. Oh my gosh, beautiful.
>> [music]
>> And again, proximity [music] to the
lake.
That is Lago Terra. Let's head on over
to Rancho Del Lago.
>> [music]
>> We go back to the map.
This was Lago Terra right off of West
Adams. [music]
Go back up Morgan's Point Road and we
have
um [music]
Rancho Del Lago.
Okay, so we [music] came up Morgan's
Point Road. We have Lago Terra, Rancho
[music] Del Lago.
There are currently 1 2 3 4 homes for
sale in Rancho Del Lago. [music] 2017
all the way up to 2026, so there's three
resales and [music] one new construction
home that's listed. Again, those
builders, they might not always [music]
list them. If you are interested, I can
reach out to the builder, get inventory
for you, see what's available, and also
see [music] if there are if there's any
availability to do a semi-custom where
you pick the lot, pick your [music]
selections. Always more expensive when
you do that, but
you know, maybe that's a preference for
[music] you. So, we're going to start
actually with the new construction
in here.
418 Dos Rios, this is priced [music] at
869.
It's a four bed, three full bath, 2800
square feet, [music] 2076
Over half acre, built right now. It's
brand new, [music] priced at 869. It
will be beautiful out front, they'll
landscape it really well.
Probably update these photos when
it's complete. [music]
You can already tell that this kitchen
is going to be fabulous. Open into the
[music] living space.
Tons of lighting always. Builder does
[music] an awesome job of letting in a
ton of natural light.
>> [music]
>> Cabinets are going in. Ooh.
All of the
>> [music]
>> homes in this community have outdoor
kitchens.
This one has an outdoor fireplace. They
might actually all have outdoor
fireplaces, but you'll have full sod and
irrigation. [music] They The homes in
here are on septic.
And on over [music] to a resale. So,
this is 0.56 acre lot, built 2017.
[music]
Four bed, three full bath, 2900 square
feet.
Priced [music] at 675.
Three car garage. Again, look at those
trees. Another pool. I love this [music]
home. Look at this They So, they
screened in the outdoor [music] sitting
area, which is great. We do get
mosquitoes. They've epoxied the
flooring. You have all of this stone out
here. Guys, this is so, [music] so
pretty.
Little fire pit sitting area.
You have Uh, this actually looks like
[music] ceramic tile wood like tile
flooring.
Tall vaulted ceilings with a beam
running through. Floor to ceiling
[music] stone fireplace. You have your
lit bookcases or shelves.
This one has
electric [music] stove.
I bring that up a lot, but you'll be
surprised by how many of my friends on
here [music] are excited that we have
that they'll have a gas
stove cuz it's just [music]
not a standard.
Carpets in most [music] of the bedrooms.
Pretty large shower.
Dual vanities, a little makeup area.
Upstairs [music] loft area they made
into a room it looks like
with the
virtual staging. Cool.
This is a bath [music] right off the
pool area. This one comes with a shed.
But guys, to get that for 675, [music]
I think is fantastic.
This is another [music] resale in there.
It's 565, originally 599. .65 [music]
acre lot, almost 3/4 of an acre lot.
Built 2019. Four bed, two and a half
bath. Smaller square footage though,
it's 2246 [music]
square feet.
And again, proximity to the lake.
>> [music]
>> Large backyard, no pool.
But huge lot, smaller home [music]
for under 600,000. All right, we're
going to go ahead on over to the Cliffs
at Lake [music] Belton. This is at the
end of Morgan's Point Road. It's the end
of Morgan's [music] Point. Um
They basically They're still building
out there.
Well, let me show you on the map.
So, Lago Terra, Rancho Del Lago, and
then Morgan's [music] Point Road runs
all the way up here. And we have the
Cliffs at Lake Belton out here. They are
still building out there. There are some
resale [music] homes.
Well, there's one resale home right now.
Then, there's
two [music] new construction homes. Only
one that's listed, which we have here.
And a builder went in and purchased up
the remaining lots from the developer,
and they're starting to build out there
with [music] him. Zoom on in.
So, we [music] come all the way up
Morgan's Point Road. You can see it's
all on a peninsula right here.
Cliffs at Lake Belton is this [music]
community, and then I have found a
beautiful $1.5 million home that has
actual [music] lake view. It's
beautiful. I'm going to show it to you.
And then I found this guy [music] at
$259,000. So, you can see a smaller or a
lower priced home
near [music] here, also. Let's take a
look.
Cliffs at Lake Belton. So, the builder
built
>> [music]
>> two homes. I actually think they're
probably the same floor plan. This one's
a resale. The owner moved. I've shown
[music] this home. It's currently
vacant. It's beautiful. Originally 975,
now 889. Three bed, three full bath,
[music] 2,900 square feet, 0.5 acre lot,
so over half acre lot. Built 2022, and
it has a pool. It's on a cul-de-sac.
[music] It's one of three cul-de-sacs in
this community.
But, this builder built only two homes.
One is now a resale, this [music] one,
and one is
um brand new for
almost the same price. Except, this one
gets a pool.
Not telling you which one is better, but
I might go for one with a pool.
These built-ins are backlit.
Almost like a contemporary [music] feel.
They virtually staged some of the rooms.
Big kitchen [music]
with these custom cabinets, quartz
countertops, beautiful
backsplash [music]
overlooking the kitchen and the living
space overlook this gorgeous backyard
[music] with a pool.
Tons of trees. [music]
You do get lots of deer out here
in this community.
Outdoor [music] kitchen, great
landscaping on this one.
This is the primary [music]
bedroom.
Double tray ceilings, they have tile
throughout
the home.
Dual vanity, soaking tub.
The shower, [music] this block, I don't
even know what this is called. This
reminds me of my grandparents home in
the that I was at in Vegas
>> [music]
>> in the
I don't know what I did to myself when I
was younger.
But they had these [music] tiles or
tiles? Windows,
glass, dual vanities, [music] looks like
granite countertops.
Beautiful shower. [music]
>> [music]
>> Laundry room with a utility sink, great
cabinet space and [music] epoxy flooring
here in the garage.
Safe room, that's important [music] to
you. And then here we are in proximity
to the lake. This one is right there,
they outlined it.
Let's see the lake right here, but it's
on that beautiful little cul-de-sac
[music] and then this is Camp Kachina
Road. It dead ends to a girl scout camp
and then this is Morgan's [music] Point
Road and it just dead ends to the lake.
So that's the resale and then the new
construction one that the builder built
backs up to it right [music] here.
Again, I think it's the same floor plan.
So this one is priced at 889 then the
one right behind [music] it is 875. So,
brand new, half acre lot, built 2026,
[music] three bed, three full bath, 2900
square feet. And they just finished it.
Outdoor kitchen.
Okay, so not exact same floor [music]
plan.
But very similar Mediterranean style.
Y'all.
If you're going [music] to have a
million-dollar home, I would hope that
you would get professional photos done.
What are these camera? This hurts my
realtor heart. Like why why are we
taking pictures [music]
with our camera?
Man.
Okay, beautiful view of the [music]
lake.
There you go. All right, so we just
checked out Cliffs at Lake Belton right
here. [music]
I'm going to show you this guy. This is
the well-priced $275,000
[music] resale. And then we'll check out
this beautiful million-dollar home on
the lake. [music]
This one is on Morgan's Point Road. It's
259,000.
>> [music]
>> Um originally 289.
Built 1977, three bed,
one full, one half bath. [music]
I think it's a little overpriced,
honestly.
Especially for where it's located. I did
see them remodeling this one [music]
some.
But cabinets are a little dated, tile
flooring, carpet in the bedrooms.
Don't get me wrong. It's a cute little
house.
>> [music]
>> But that's what 200 and
59,000 can get you here in Morgan's
Point.
>> [music]
>> Then we're going to take a look at
Oh, this one. So, this one is on like it
has the most beautiful view of the lake.
[music] I saw this one in person also.
So, so, so, so pretty. I actually met
with the owner. I was walking the
property.
>> [music]
>> He was just kind of telling me the
history of it. It was really sweet.
Four bed, three and a half bath. [music]
They are including this livable space
above the garage. Two [music] acre lot.
Built 2009. 1.5 million.
So, this is the main house. It is
[music] a two-story. You have this
garage space with this livable space
above it.
Look at [music] that. You it's actually
a cliff. Like that is the property. It
overlooks the lake. [music]
It It's I can't even describe how
beautiful that view is.
Okay, so starting with the main house,
you have a beautiful [music] porch.
That view is from your front your
backyard, the [music]
off the kitchen.
Just so pretty.
That's the [music] entryway.
Wood flooring.
Beautiful [music] banister.
Very custom-built home. Your living
space, your kitchen
overlooking the backyard [music]
with the most beautiful lake view. Look
at that. Can you imagine cooking
breakfast or cooking dinner [music]
and having a glass of wine or margarita
if you're me and just having that view?
it's just to [music] die for.
Tons of lighting.
Very blue [music] room.
This is upstairs. You have an upstairs
[music] patio.
This is off that [music] garage living
quarter.
I think this could make an
>> [music]
>> amazing Airbnb.
It'd be a pricey one.
But these lots are really long.
So, this is the property. They're super
long lots.
I think [music] they go something like
that.
But really beautiful luxury listing on
the lake here
in Morgan's Point Resort. So, hopefully
this video gave you a much better idea
of what some of these homes within these
communities around Lake Belton actually
[music] look like. If there's a specific
neighborhood near Belton, Temple,
Salado, Nolanville, any of the
surrounding areas that you would like me
to get video [music] on, drop it in the
comments. I'll work on getting that for
you. And if you're relocating to the
Central Texas area, I'd love to be your
guide. Till next time, I'm Andrea Cudic,
your Central [music] Texas relocation
expert.